Childhood asthma returnedPosted 2 months agoHi, as a child I had quite bad asthma with a few hospital stays because of it, however as I grew older it dissappeared. In 2010 I have an anxiety disorder which was mistake for asthma however a manatol challenge come back negative so asthma was dismissed. Now always 6 years later iv started to get some wheezing in bed but no shortness off breath. I got a ventolin inhaler from my sister to try and this cleared the wheezing straight away. Now I have a bad cough which wakes me up early hours of the morning with wheezing and I also cough when I go out in the cold weather. My question is my doctor seems to think it cannot be asthma as my mannitol challenge came back negative, however in my opinion if my asthma was just not symptomatic at the time does this not mean it would not of showed up? Any help would be a big help ☺