Weird peak flow. Does this ever happen?________________________________________Hi there! new girl here. 👋I have to wonder about something really strange that happens when I use my peak flow meter. I have been using it pretty consistently now for a week trying to determine what my personal best is. I am noticing that the very very first time I use it on a given day, no matter what time, it is extremely high! And the subsequent readings are much much lower. (But close to the average for my height and age)Example: this am i got up and blew a 650.😳. All readings since then were around 400. Even after 2 puffs of xopenex. No change.Same thing pretty much yesterday. My very first attempt of the day was 550. Then right around 400 everything after. Same the day before. Is something wrong with my meter? I certainly don't 'feel' different from 1 attempt to the next. And I seem to be doing it the same way each time.Does this happen to anyone else?