Just found this. It's helped me to read it, it may help others?Patients & relatives / Life with bowel cancer / Our Cancer Experiences (it's a long story!)on: March 19, 2014, 09:35:24 AM Started by Lawsonsheir, Message by LawsonsheirRelevance: 24.4%In August 1985 Age 35, married 10 years, with 2 sons aged 4 and 9 months, I developed pain in my back and groin area which steadily became worse over next 8 months or so. There were multiple GP appointments and home visits in the middle of the night and several admissions to hospital but nothing was detected.Then in May 1986, my GP found a large lump in my abdomen. I was admitted to the Royal Gwent Hospital (RGH) the same day. Subsequent tests revealed a large tumour on the back of my abdomen wrapped around my spine, blood vessels and the tube from my right kidney which had been blocked and had caused the pain. I underwent an exploratory operation to take a biopsy. The morning after the operation my right leg was blocked with Deep Vein Thromboses from top to bottom.A biopsy showed that I had a testicular tumour – obviously not in the usual place! A couple of weeks after the operation I was well enough to give my sister away at her wedding.Referred to Velindre Cancer Centre under the care of consultant Keith James. Underwent 4 months of chemotherapy – absolutely horrendous, was sick every 20 minutes or so for 3 or so days after. Modern anti-sickness drugs were not available back then. . My wife nursed me at home and had to look after the kids as well (she is descended from Angells on her father’s side ϑ ) And that was that as far as Velindre were concerned and I went back to work.Christmas 1985, the pain returned along with other symptoms. More investigations including a CT scan (very new back then) showed another tumour in a different place. News was delivered by three very grim faced doctors who when I asked gave my chances of a cure as 50/50. But Keith James said he was going “to hit it with everything” he had. And by God he did!I underwent 6 months of intensive chemotherapy of a combination of 4 different drugs which made me extremely ill. Even worse sickness than previously (nursed again by my “Angell”), followed by 1 month of radiotherapy which was almost as bad. I managed to return to work part-time through the chemotherapy after the worse side effects had worn off but was unable to do so through the radiotherapy.And so I went on to “follow-up” with regular CT scans and check-ups. I went through treatment alongside another patient by the name of David from Cardiff and we became friendly. On one of my check-ups at Velindre I asked how David was doing only to be told that sadly he’d died. That knocked me for six!So life went back to normal(ish). I learned to live with the problems the surgery and treatment had caused me. And my career progressed, life returned more or less to normal.Then in 1999, I noticed blood in my bowel movements. Was referred for a bowel examination and was told I had “a large polyp” and that I needed more surgery which was subsequently booked. I only found out the truth when shortly before I was to be admitted to RGH for the operation I went to see my GP for a medical certificate for the time off. He looked at my notes and said “oh, I am sorry” and “what do you want me to write on the certificate?” I said just put what it is. It was only when I got home and opened the certificate that I saw he’d written Sigmoid Carcinoma. My wife and I went into shock for a couple of weeks before realising we just had to deal with it.I underwent the surgery in June when my elder son was sitting his A levels. The tumour was removed and the bowel rejoined. The operation seemed to have gone well but it turned out I had more deep vein thromboses in my right leg so they had to be treated as well. On microscopic examination the tumour turned out to be Dukes B which meant it hadn’t spread so I didn’t need chemotherapy or radiotherapy this time.Back to work again for a few months, then on my 50th birthday!!!! I noticed I was once again passing blood. Various tests including a colonoscopy revealed another bowel tumour. So back to RGH again for another operation – this time an AP resection - removal of the lower part of my large bowel, my rectum and my anus and the formation of a colostomy. I would have to wear a pouch to collect the output from my bowel. The consultant at Velindre, Alison Brewster, who had also been involved in my treatment back in 1986/87 decided it would be a good idea to undergo chemotherapy even though the tumour was again Dukes B. With the help of the more modern anti-sickness drugs it was much easier this time and the fact that I wasn’t working meant that I was able to cope better with the other side effects such as sore mouth and throat and tiredness.This time I decided it was time to give up work to enjoy whatever time I had left (I really didn’t know) with my family.So I did and despite various limitations imposed by my swollen right leg and various other side effects of the 3 lots of surgery, life returned more or less to normal. Normal insofar as once a cancer patient there is a tendency to imagine that every little ache or pain is another episode!In 2007, I developed a nagging pain low down on the right hand side of my abdomen. Was referred back to RGH and after several months of tests found out (by accident again) that I had another bowel tumour in my Caecum – the bit between the small and large intestines. So Mr Swarnkar, one of the bowel surgeons decided to remove the remainder of my large bowel – a total colectomy – to repair the colostomy and give me an ileostomy. I’d have a stoma on my right side and would have to wear a pouch to collect the output from the small bowel.The operation turned out to be a nightmare for the surgical team due to scarring from the radiotherapy back in 1987 and adhesions (bits stuck together) from previous operations. Also the small bowel tore in several places and had to be repaired. I understand that the operation took about 10 hours and afterwards was taken to the High Dependency Unit. Over the next couple of days I developed complications and became unable to breathe for myself so I was put into a medically induced coma and placed on life support in the Intensive Care Unit. I remained in the coma for about 3 weeks and there were a number of occasions when my family were told I might not survive. I had MRSA pneumonia, collapsed lungs, my kidney failed (the other one was destroyed by the tumour in 1985); I had heart problems and another drug resistant infection known as VRE Vancomycin Resistant Enterococcus. I developed a bedsore and my muscles wasted away to such an extent that when I came out of the coma I could do nothing for myself – not even lift a spoonful of Weetabix. Following a few weeks of recovery I was sent to the Rehabilitation Unit at St Woolos where I spent a couple of weeks learning to walk again and generally to look after myself. I went home mid-January 2008.I was referred to the Cancer Genetics Service as were concerned that my cancers may have been hereditary. They turned out not to be and the conclusion was that my bowel cancers had been caused by the radiotherapy back in 1987. I believe that the footballer, Bobby Moore, experienced the same situation.It will probably come as no surprise that I’ve never fully recovered from that episode. I’m not very mobile, walk with the aid of a stick around the house and have to use a mobility scooter for longer outings. And I still have all sorts of problems resulting form the various surgeries, treatments and the spell in Intensive Care. But life goes on and we make the best of what we’ve got.In 2008 my wife was diagnosed with breast cancer. She had chemotherapy, followed by a mastectomy and then radiotherapy. I think our experience with my episodes of cancer helped us both to cope with yet another devastating diagnosis and I was able to repay my wife to some small extent by helping to nurse and care for her through her treatment. We both still need help with personal care and we help and support each other.In 2010 I developed a raw patch of skin on my back which was subsequently found to be skin cancer – Basal Cell Carcinoma. I had it removed under local anaesthetic and the good news was that it wasn’t the type that spreads.A point I’d like to make is that cancer is not a death sentence as it once was. It is a treatable illness and there are many people like me who have survived it and indeed who live with it under control – a chronic illness like many others.I’d also like to point out that the families of cancer patients often suffer more than the patients themselves. I have never had to endure anything unbearable but I do know how easy it is for relatives to think that what their loved ones are going through must be unbearable. Seeing suffering is often worse than experiencing it. And I know that my sons, now in late twenties and early thirties, have both been affected in different ways by our illnesses over the years.Finally I’d like to say I’m just an ordinary bloke, not a fighter, just a submitter (to the treatments) and I don’t regard my experiences as “battles”. I’ve never been given “the all clear” and it disturbs me when I hear patients at the beginning of their journeys say they have. The treatment is tough but it can be worth it in the end.I’ve been encouraged to post our “stories” as I’m told that some cancer patients find strength and support from reading of others’ experiences. I do hope that this proves to be the case. Furthermore if I can be of any help, please do not hesitate to contact me.Graham