Spinal fusion overHi everyone, day 3 in hospital and doing well considering the major surgery i have undergone. I have 2 metal plates in my back with screws fusing my spine and all this was done through the stomach. I was put onto a sliding scale which took the pressure off me being in theatre for 3 hours and feeling nauseous on waking. They just fed anti sickness drugs through venflon and i tested my BMs which weren't too erratic. Bit high last night 18.1 coming off the scale but with my correction and sall amount of food and insulin to clover it back between 8-10 which is better 😃