Blood sugar levelsI was in Cornwall last week and went for a coffee in a garden centre cafe at Bude.  Every now and again, especially when on holiday, I treat myself to a piece of cake or something similar.  They didn't have lemon drizzle cake, my favourite choice, so I opted for a cranberry and white chocolate slice.  When I bit into it, it was unbelievably sweet. I thought my blood sugar levels would go through the roof but thought it probably wouldn't do any harm as a one off.  I was diagnosed Type2, 6 months ago and use diet to control my blood sugar levels.I tested before I ate the cake and then tested 1½ hours later.  Much to my surprise I went from 6.6 to 7.3.  I was expecting a reading of well over 10.  Could this mean that I am better able to deal with blood sugar and becoming less diabetic?  I have lost 2 stone in weight over the past 6 months having been very strict with my low carb diet.  I seem to have hit a plateau with my weight now but I have got rid of a lot of excess fat.  I have bags of energy too and spend most of my days in the garden, digging and weeding.   