Co-morbidity and other health conditionsHi,Does anyone else have other health conditions alongside diabetes? I always seem to be at the doctors for something and feel like the only one. As well as the T1, I have cavus foot deformity and an undiagnosed condition which means that the muscles in my lower legs are permanently contracted causing pain. For this I'm supposed to have an operation to lengthen the muscles and lower my heel arch as well as remove the scarred tissue from the ligaments (from the repeated times I've sprained and twisted my ankles). Recently (in the last 5 years) I have been suffering from infrequent hand spasms causing my left hand to either go 'claw shaped' or tighten into a fist. This is extremely painful but only happens about once every two months. Recently though it's been happening more often. I was wondering if they were connected (my hand and legs) and then maybe thought it could be related to the diabetes or the diabetes could be another condition caused by another more serious condition. I have even started wondering if my parents dropped me on my head as a child and this has something to do with it all.Anyway, if anyone else has more than one condition or anything similar to these it would be good to get in touch.80 years with Type 1Last month, Joslin awarded Dr. C Kenneth Gorman the Lifetime Achievement Award for living for 80 years with ‪#‎insulin‬-dependent (‪#‎type1‬) ‪#‎diabetes‬. Dr. Gorman is one of five recipients of the 80-year medal and the only Canadian recipient thus far. In 1935, at the age of two, Dr. Gorman was diagnosed with ‪#‎T1D‬. He went on to become an ‪#‎endocrinologist‬ and worked as a research fellow under Dr. Charles Best, one of the co-discovers of insulin. During his time with Dr. Best, Dr. Gorman began corresponding with Dr. Elliott Joslin and accepted a position as an N.I.H. Trainee Fellow in Diabetes at the Joslin Clinic from 1962 to 1964. Dr. Gorman's next goal is to celebrate the 100th anniversary of the discovery of Insulin in 2021. Congratulations, Dr. Gorman! 

Amazing!   He worked with Charles Best as well!  